

□+1 425 623 7592 | **☑** yo@micmax.pw | **⑥** www.micmax.pw | **⑤** mic-max | **ऻ** micmax

Summary

Recent university graduate. 7+ years of programming experience, with a focus in backend development and software engineering. In between schoolwork I like attending hackathons and exploring hobbyist electronics. I'm very interested in parallel & distributed computing where performance metrics are critical. Seeking job opportunities in North America for a role I can mature into and become an effective addition to the team.

Skills_

Languages + Libraries JavaScript, Python, C/C++, React, CSS, SQL, MongoDB **Development** Git, Linux, Azure, Serverless, Test-Driven Development

Work Experience ____

Microsoft Redmond, Washington

SOFTWARE ENGINEER — EDGE EXPERIMENTATION

Jun. 2019 - Present

- · Parsing feature flags information from source code such as default states per platform to create useful systems for our engineers to understand the current state of the thousands of flags and monitor changes we receive from Chromium.
- Developing rules for a bot that is part of a pull request validation workflow, knowledgable on Azure functions and how to use them with ADO web hooks and other serverless resources available on Azure.

Martello Technologies Kanata, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER — SUMMER STUDENT

Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Replaced a legacy dashboard with a Vue.js application which iteracted with our REST API
- Developed resuable custom Vue.js UI components for our internal library (e.g. a modal, a filtered sorted table)
- · Created a suite of Mocha tests on currently supported CRUD operations of containers and devices
- · Presented my progress at biweekly sprint meetings to the management team, shareholders, and all other developers

Carleton University: School of Computer Science

Ottawa, Canada

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Sept. 2016 - Dec. 2018

- Comp 2406: Fundamentals of Web Applications & Comp 1406: Introduction to Computer Science II
- · Held office hours, organised and ran weekly workshops following the course's content and assignments
- · Graded assignments using a rubric that all teaching assistants collaborated in creating together

Projects

Android Application — Blitz SMS

Ottawa, Canada

Lead Developer — Created for a 3^{RD} year software engineering course

Sept. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- · An android application that can make requests to our multiple services and presents the data in a relevant manner
- · Server makes API requests to answer the user's request and send that back using the linked twilio number
- Managed a team of four students and assigned weekly tasks, reviewed pull requests, and developed the server using a unique transfer protocol
- · Our client-server architecture made use of several design patterns such as: Singleton, Strategy, Template Method, Facade, and Retry

8 Bit Breadboard CPU Ottawa, Canada

DESIGN INSPIRED BY A BEN EATER SERIES ON YOUTUBE

Sep. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Recreated an 8 Bit CPU on a series of breadboards using mostly 74LS TTL components to develop a greater understanding of the fundamentals of how computers function. I was able to create and run very simple programs in the Turing complete system's bytecode
- Goal: Scale it to 16 bits and add more ram for more complex programs and create a simple compiler for its bytecode

Education

Carleton University Ottawa, Canada

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE HONOURS: SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2015 - Apr. 2019

· Parallel Programming, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Software Quality Assurance, Software Product Management

• David A. Thomas Scholarship in Computer Science for achieving a 10.0 CGPA

MICHAEL MAXWELL · RÉSUMÉ LAST UPDATED · APRIL 23, 2021